all right
[Music]
approximately one in seven American
adults have chronic kidney disease and
the prevalence is higher in those with
metabolic risk factors such as high
blood pressure diabetes and obesity that
sounds like a job for plant-based diets
which have demonstrated significant
utility for the prevention and treatment
of all three of those modern day
scourges of society
their utility for the treatment of so
many diseases has led to a growing
interest in their applicability for the
prevention and treatment of chronic
kidney disease itself
in theory there are multiple benefits of
more plant-based diets in the management
of kidney disease the intake of animal
fat is associated with protein loss in
the urine and other components related
to meat such as choline and carnitine
are converted by bad gut bugs into tmao
which is associated with scarring of the
kidneys plant-based diets carry a
decreased acid load whereas ingestion of
animal-based foods like meat eggs and
dairy increases the formation of acid
and ammonia unlike the favorable
alkalization from fruits and vegetables
the phosphorus in plant-based protein is
less absorbable which is a good thing if
you have alien kidneys especially
compared to the added phosphorus-based
preservatives that are often used in
meat processing indeed you can
successfully lower blood phosphorus
levels and kidney disease patients in as
short as one week on a vegetarian diet
High dietary fiber intake can also pull
Advanced glycation and products out of
your system those so-called glycotoxins
and prevent constipation which can cause
potassium overload in kidney patients a
plant-based diet also lessens the
likelihood of exposure to
potassium-based additives a lot of the
phosphorus additives in meat are also
potassium additives and finally there
may be favorable impacts on the gut
microbiome leading to lower generation
of uremic toxins such putrefaction
products are generated by protein
putrifying in the gut but plant-rich
dyes may be able to reduce uremic toxins
in part due to increased fiber and lower
protein intakes
the lower the dietary protein intake the
slower the progression towards end-stage
kidney disease and the increased risk of
progression to end-stage kidney disease
associated with dietary protein intake
appeared to have no threshold meaning it
just seemed the lower the better but
even if you just drop your protein
intake by just like 10 grams a day that
modest reduction May decrease the risk
of end-stage renal disease and death by
greater than 50 percent that's
incredible it was a randomized control
trial they were trying to get people
down to like 0.6 grams per kilogram a
day of protein which is like 40 grams a
day but could only get people down to
about 60 grams a day which is
technically not even a low protein diet
the recommended protein intake is 0.8
grams per kilogram per day or like 50
grams a day but just getting people from
the usual protein intake of like 70
grams down to 60. cut their risk of
dialysis or death by 77 percent check
this out
by the end of four years more than 25
percent of those in the usual diet group
were either dead or on dialysis from end
stage disease in the reduced protein
group it was less than 10 percent
a randomized controlled trial proving
massive benefit yet despite strong
scientific evidence many doctors are
still unconvinced that a low protein
diet can help patients with chronic
kidney disease why
the reasons for this nihilism are
unclear but could be related to
insufficient background knowledge lack
of interest in nutrition and dietetics
and limited familiarity with the most
recent scientific literature
foreign